Teach him a lesson.
给我好好解决这个人
I want him not to go
我要让他有十个胆
against me forever.
也不敢跟我对着干
Keep him alive or not?
留活口吗
This is Lanhe Restaurant
兰和料理店
who called
往当铺打电话的
the pawnshop.
就是这儿
I've been here before.
我来过这家店
Really?
你来过
I followed the suspect here
金门饭店行动那天
on the day for the case of Jinmen Hotel.
我跟着凶手来到这家店
But I lost him.
但我当时并没有找到他
Have a look inside.
进去看看
Hello.
你好
Okay, got it.
好 明白了
Excuse me.
打扰一下
Good afternoon, here is the menu.
中午好 这是菜单
Thank you.
谢谢
Excuse me.
你好
A friend of mine
我有个朋友
has booked a dinner
前两天在你们店里面
2 days before.
预订了一桌晚餐
But he wanna change
里面有一种鱼
one kind of the fish.
他想换成另外一种
I have to inform the waiter.
我得告知那个店员
Which kind do you want?
您想换成什么鱼
I can write it for you.
我帮您记也是一样的
Replace eel with saury.
他想把鳗鱼换成秋刀鱼
Yes.
对
Saury is okay.
换成刀鱼
He has other requirements
我那位朋友要求比较多
like persimmon leaves
比如说配菜
in season
一定要现在
for side dish.
当季的柿子叶
We wanna
所以我们想
confirm with the waiter directly.
跟店员确认一下
Yes.
对
For an order 2 days ago,
两天前的话
Yoshida should be responsible.
应该是吉田君
But he asked for a leave.
可是吉田君请假了
Yoshida?
吉田君
Hideo Yoshida.
吉田英夫
He's responsible for
平时是他专门负责
reservation and external contact.
预订和对外联络的
However,
但是
he asked for
他刚刚请了
a week's leave
一个星期的假
Do you know where he lives?
那你知道他住哪儿吗
Or where else
或者他平时除了料理店
does he usually go?
还会去什么别的地方吗
He seems like a student.
吉田君好像是位学生
But
但是
he never speaks of
他从来都不提
himself.
自己的事
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Will you go home after work?
你今天下班回家吗
No.
不回去
Why?
还不回去
I haven't gone home for days.
我已经好几天没回去
I have to go back.
得回去看看
Textbooks...
教科书
Japanese school uniform...
日本校服
This logo
这个图案
looks like a school badge.
看起来像是校徽
Can you recognize it?
能看出来是哪所学校吗
No.
看不出来
The button is the same as the one
这扣子和骆珉敏捡到的
Minmin picked up.
一模一样
The murderer...
凶手
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Sir,
先生
are you dinning alone?
您一个人吗
On the day we handled the Jinmen Hotel case,
金门饭店行动那天
Hideo Yoshida
应该就是这个
probably learned
叫吉田英夫的
about my apartment
接到当铺老板电话
through the pawnshop's phone
知道了我公寓的地址
and drove over
也是他开车到现场
to pick up the killer.
接走了凶手
All our attention
我们只注意到
was paid to the police uniform
凶手穿的是警服
worn by the killer,
却忽略了他警服下面
not to the clothes inside.
穿的是什么
So, the button
照这么说
Minmin pulled down should be
骆珉敏就是从校服
from the school uniform inside.
拽下来的扣子
What we should do next is
眼下要做的
to confirm the school which
就是查到这个校服
the uniform belongs to.
来自于哪所学校
Are you OK?
你没事吧
Yes.
我没事
What about you?
你怎么样
I'm fine.
我应该也没事
Let's leave here first.
先赶紧离开这儿吧
That's all?
没了
The wallet might drop
钱包应该是
when I flung.
在扑倒的时候甩出去了
Sir.
老板
A bowl of noodles.
一碗面
Only one?
一碗啊
OK.
好
May I use this?
老板借用一下
Two bowls, please.
老板两碗面
OK.
好
Do you think that
你觉得刚刚
was a death threat just now?
那算死亡威胁吗
As long as
他们要是觉得算
those people think so.
那就算吧
What's your plan next?
你接下来什么打算
Continue investigating.
该怎么查怎么查
I won't give up now.
我是不会现在放弃的
Who do you think
那你觉得
they're sent by?
刚刚是谁派来的人
Feng Guangyun.
冯广云
If it's true,
如果真要是冯广云
you'll suffer more
你再查下去
than suspension.
就不是停职这么简单了
It's the school badge.
校徽的图案
Gosh, you can remember it at a glance.
你居然看一眼就记住了
I'll investigate myself.
接下来我自己查吧
That's obviously
那套校服的样式
a Japanese school uniform.
是明显的日式校服
I have
我认识几个
some friends in the government.
在政府做事的朋友
They may find the school
应该能从教育局查到
from the Education Bureau.
是哪所日本学校
No, it's not working.
教育局是查不到的
No registration is required
日本人在上海办学校
for Japanese schools.
是不会跟我们登记的
They're managed
他们的学校
by the Japanese Residents' Association.
都由居留民团管理
What is it?
居留民团
An autonomous group of expatriates.
对 日本侨民自治团体
We can never get any information
居留民团不可能
from the group.
透露线索给我们
I knew
我知道几个
some textile mills for uniforms.
做制服的纺织厂
I'll do the investigation.
还是我去查吧
You're not clear about the conditions here.
上海情况你不太了解
Aren't you afraid of being dismissed?
你就不怕停职变撤职啊
If so,
我要是怕的话
I'd already stopped
早就收手了
and wouldn't think of it.
也不会等到今天
What are you doing?
你干吗
Eating noodles.
吃面啊
Have I said giving it to you?
我有说分给你吗
You never pay for noodles!
每一次吃面你都不掏钱
I paid it
我刚刚不是
just now.
给了一枚铜板吗
Protect yourself
下回救人之前啊
before saving others.
先保护好自己
I'm protecting you.
那不是怕你死了
Sir.
老板
Gimme a bowl, please.
拿个碗
No problem.
好啊
Put it higher.
好 再高点儿
Higher.
高点儿
No.
对 不行不行不行
Lower.
低点
No, higher.
不行 高
Higher.
高
Too much.
过 过 过了
Lower.
低点
OK.
好
Hold on.
别动
Everybody looks at me.
来 大家看这里啊
Smile.
笑一个
Cheese.
笑
Three, two, one.
三 二 一
Go.
走
OK.
好嘞
Thank you.
谢谢骆师傅
You're welcome.
不客气
We are neighbors.
都街里街坊的
I didn't expect you
我以为这个老六
to have
是最后一个
a son again.
又有个小七出来了
We like more sons.
儿不嫌多嘛
Just need to prepare more food.
就是添双筷子的事儿
Indeed.
没错
Mr. Luo,
骆师傅
when will the photo be ready?
照片啥时候过来取啊
You can ask Minmin
你们这样啊
for it
后天啊找珉敏来拿
the day after tomorrow.
就可以了
Don't worry.
你们放心
She's been learning to take photos
她现在已经跟着我
from me.
学手艺了
She can run the shop
顶多半年
within half a year.
打理铺子没问题
Running a photo shop
这女孩儿啊
is suitable for a girl.
打理照相馆
It keeps out wind and rain.
风吹不着 雨淋不着
Great!
合适
Yes.
没错
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢
Miss Luo
这骆警官
is busy every day.
每天已经忙不过来了
Apart from the police work,
人家一边当警察
she has to run the shop.
还得要打理你这铺子
Don't you
你呀
feel bad for her?
真不心疼你闺女
She isn't a police officer anymore.
她现在已经不当警察了
Running
你想
the shop is easier
这打理铺子
than working in the police.
不比当警察自在啊
Isn't it?
对不对 珉敏
Look at my children.
你看我生的这两个
That's enough.
行行行 少说两句
If I had such a girl...
我要是有这么
They're all good.
都好 都好啊
We need to go.
骆师傅你先忙
All good.
都好
The day after tomorrow.
后天啊
I didn’t finish.
话还没说完
OK.
后天
I keep it in mind.
行 行 行
Thank you.
骆师傅你忙啊
Fine.
行
See you next time.
那我们先走
Bye.
好
See you.
好 我们先走了啊
Goodbye.
好嘞
Remember the date.
后天啊
Sure.
行行行 好嘞
Don't forget it.
后天 好
No problem.
走 走好
Bye.
后天
Hey girl.
这个小姑娘
Why do you wanna be a police officer?
为什么想当警察啊
Sir,
报告所长
because I wanna
我当警察
protect my family.
是因为想要保护家人
Luo...
骆
Luo Minmin.
骆珉敏
I know you.
对对对 我知道你
You're the girl
考了最后一名
ranking last.
那个小丫头
Don't be shy.
不要不好意思嘛
You are in the same level.
这几个跟你差不多
Pretty close.
八九不离十
Luo Minmin.
骆珉敏
You caught a thief
第一次出警
on your first mission.
就抓着个小偷
You deserve praise.
值得表扬
Really?
真的
Miss Luo,
骆警官
you're kind.
你很善良
If you wanna be
如果你想要
a good police officer,
做一名好警察的话
do the right things you think.
做你认为正确的事情
Captain Chen is right.
陈队长说得对
You will be a good police officer.
你能成为一个好的警察
At least you have
至少比我
more chances than me.
更有可能
Dad.
爸
You forced
你天天
Minmin to stay at home
把姐这么关在家里
every day.
不让她出门
What if she's feeling down?
不怕她憋坏了呀
She's probably gonna
我就怕她
work at the police station again
被别人夸几句
after being praised.
又回去当警察了
I understand.
我知道
But
但你去看看
look at her now.
她现在那个样子
She used to argue with me.
之前天天跟我吵
But now
现在安静得
she is as timid as a rabbit.
像只兔子一样
Isn't it your wish?
那不是如你所愿吗
Mr. Xiang!
向警官
Finally!
我终于找到你了
I went to the Fourth Station.
我去四所找你啊
They said you'd moved here.
他们说你搬到这儿了
Why are you here?
你怎么
Can you go to my home tonight?
晚上你能来一趟我家吗
What's wrong?
怎么了
Is Miss Luo getting worse?
骆警官情况严重了
No.
没有没有没有
But she is in a dilemma.
不过她现在还挺惨的
She is locked in home
天天被我爸关在家里面
by my father.
不让她出门
I've
这不
come up with a solution.
我想了个办法
But I need your help.
需要你帮忙
Can you?
行吗 向警官
My sister needs you.
我姐现在真的很需要你
I got you.
知道了
Thank you. See you tonight.
谢谢 晚上见
Who is she?
这是谁啊
Luo Minmin's sister.
骆珉敏她妹妹
Does she need any help?
找你有事啊
She asked me to visit Luo Minmin
说是让我去她家
in her home.
看看骆警官
Shouldn't my team members
现在队员有事
turn to me for help first?
不应该第一个找我吗
But why to you?
为什么找你啊
Because
因为
I'm the partner of Miss Luo.
我和骆警官是搭档
And she got injured because of me.
而且她受伤我也有责任
It's reasonable for us to care
互相之间关心一下
for each other.
很合理
Indeed.
合理
Sounds great.
这个合理
Follow me.
走啊
Sir,
先生
do you like sailing?
你喜欢船吗
My niece likes it.
我侄子喜欢船
He told me the story of
他还跟我讲过
Magellan sailing around the world.
麦哲伦环球航行的故事
Have you heard of it?
你听过吗
I only heard about
我只听过巴尔沃亚
the story of Balboa
第一个发现
who found the Pacific.
太平洋的故事
Nice to meet you.
你好
I'm Qiao Jianshi.
我是乔建石
I'm Shi Junyu
我是石珺昱
I saw the code
我是在报纸上
on the newspaper.
看到我们的接头暗号的
I've been sent to inform you
上级安排我来和你接头
of three tasks.
一共有三件事
First.
第一
You need to contact
你需要唤醒
a comrade in rest.
一名休眠中的同志
He is the only subordinate
他一直是邓铭远同志
of Deng Mingyuan.
单线联系的下线
He's entrusted
现在他将这名同志
to us
托付给组织
for teamwork.
重新启用
You'll be
今后就由你
his superior in the future.
来担任他的上线
I'll contact him soon.
好 我尽快和他接头
Second.
第二
This photo is from
这张照片
the national salvation organization.
是救国会交给我的
You may know the person in it.
上面的人你应该认得
Who took the photo?
这张照片是谁拍的
A patriotic journalist
《申报》
surnamed Peng of Shen Bao.
一名姓彭的爱国记者
Also a member of the NSO.
他也是救国会的委员
I heard
我听上级说
you're investigating the murder case.
你在追查孟家案的凶手
When the killed is found,
如果找到凶手了
you may need to think
你可能需要
how to deal with him
根据照片上的内容
according to the picture.
慎重考虑如何处理他
I got it.
好 我知道了
How about the transmitter
你负责保管的那部电台
you're in charge of?
现在什么情况
It's originally a 100-watt
之前是一百瓦的
Hartley transmitter.
哈特莱发报机
I used it in my apartment.
但是我在公寓试过了
The light flickered.
灯泡会闪
Besides, the electronic monitoring
而且最近电子监测
is stricter.
越来越严
So, I turned it into a 50-watt one.
所以我改成了五十瓦
The higher-ups decided to restart it
上级决定重启这部电台
for contact
负责中央
between Shanghai and the Central.
和上海方面的联络
This is the third task.
这也是你第三个任务
But
但是
we are shorthanded now.
现在人手紧缺
We don't have operators,
没有专门的机务员
telegraph operators or interpreters.
报务员和译电员
That's to say,
也就是说
you need to be
这部电台的所有工作
responsible
都需要由你
for all these
一个人来完成
yourself.
没事
I can.
我都会
Work can be resumed at any time.
我随时准备恢复工作
The transmitter
在这个时候
has to be restarted now.
启用你的电台
Because it's
是因为关系到
related to the pivotal task.
组织的最高任务
Our nation is in danger.
国难当头
But someone haven't awakened.
仍有人在沉睡
The situation is severe.
现在形势已经十分严峻
All patriots must be united to fight
必须团结一切爱国者
and force Chiang
奋起反抗
to resist Japanese invaders.
逼蒋抗日
The whole nation
尽快让全民族同胞
should pool efforts.
齐心抗战
The NSO is
而救国会是这股合力的
an important part.
重要组成部分
It's the top target of the united front.
也是统战的首要目标
You're required
上级决定从现在开始
to continue leading the group
由你继续领导这支小组
and join the plan of the NSO.
参与统战救国会的计划
Mrs. Ji
季太太
will be
将担任
an intermediary between you
你和救国会之间的
and the NSO.
联络员
And the transmitter
你的电台
is used to contact Shanghai and the Central.
负责联通上海和中央
I got it.
我知道了
Deng Mingyuan
这个
gave me this letter in prison.
是他在监狱里给我的
My original purpose in coming
我这次来上海
to Shanghai
原本是为了
was to carry out the rescue plan.
执行营救计划
But he refused the plan
邓铭远同志知道
even he knew that
回到南京就意味着牺牲
returning
但他还是
to Nanjing meant sacrifice.
拒绝了这个计划
He hoped
他说现在
that CPC can preserve its strength
是最艰难的时候
in the most difficult times,
希望组织保存力量
rather than falling into
不要再有同志
a more dangerous situation to rescue him.
为了营救他而涉险
Following his instructions,
我按照他给的地址
I retrieved this key to a safe
取到了这把汇丰银行
at HSBC.
保险柜的钥匙
Inside are the last funds
里面是孟先生和孟太太
Mr. and
最后一次
Mrs. Meng
为依斯克拉计划
raised for ISKRA.
筹集的资金
The key is now yours.
钥匙就交给你了
Your team
依斯克拉计划
has been
能够走到今天
supporting ISKRA
没有中断
without interruption.
是因为你们这支小组
The higher-ups
上级让我
asked me to express
为你们所做的一切
praise and respect
提出表彰
for all you've done,
并为小组每一位成员的
and each and every
付出和牺牲
sacrifice.
表达敬意
Deng Mingyuan did this
邓铭远同志放弃营救
to help us
是为了我们
go further.
可以走得更远
Even if in the end
哪怕走到最后
only one comrade remains,
只剩下一名同志
as long as the fight continues,
只要还在继续战斗
his efforts will not be in vain.
他的苦心就没有白费
Sir, we're closed now.
警官我们已经打烊了
What can I do for you?
您有什么事儿吗
Mr. Fan.
范老板
Can you finally
到底是谁
tell me who was looking for
找到了照片上的女孩
the girl in the photo?
现在可以说了吧
It's...
麻 麻将馆
a call from the mahjong parlor.
是麻将馆打来的电话
You seem so tense. Calm down.
你太紧张了 放轻松
Take it easy.
放轻松啊范老板
Hurry up!
赶紧的
Bring me my fruit platter!
把我的果盘给我拿过来
Here, pour some water!
来倒杯水 倒杯水啊
Right away!
好好好
Yes.
是
I was the one who called
这地址的确是我打电话
the pawnshop with the address.
告诉东光当铺的
Actually,
是这么回事儿
I have a handyman working for me
我手底下有一个伙计
named Luo Tianxiang.
打杂的 叫骆天祥
He said
是他
he saw the girl
说碰巧在街上
going home by chance on the street.
看见这个女孩儿回家的
Is he here?
人在店里吗
You mean Luo Tianxiang?
谁 骆天祥啊
No, he's off today.
他请假 今天没来
Give me his address.
把他的地址给我
I don't remember it
他家具体地址这我
exactly.
记不太清楚了
But his father
不过他家呢
opened a
在我这附近
photo studio nearby.
开了一家照相馆
How about
要不这么着吧
I call
我打电话
Captain Chen at the
给警察四所的陈队
Fourth Station?
问问他
Tianxiang's sister
天祥的妹妹
is a police officer
正好在四所里边
there.
也做警察
Chen will definitely know
陈队长肯定知道
the address.
具体地址
A police officer?
他妹妹是警察
Yes.
对呀
She's injured days before.
前段时间还受了伤呢
Actually,
其实天祥请假
Tianxiang took a leave
就是因为要回家
to take care of her.
照顾他妹妹
It's a sad family story.
这家人怪可怜的
Well,
扯远了
I'll call Captain Chen
我现在就打电话
right now.
问四所的陈队长啊
No need.
不用了
Why?
不
He must know the address.
他知道具体地址
I'll...
我给您
No need.
不用了
Sir.
这位警官
Which station are you from?
您是哪个所的呀
You don't
听您这口音
sound local...
也不像本地人
Hello?
喂
Please connect me
帮我接警察局
to the Fourth Station of Shiliupu.
十六铺分局第四警察所
Yes.
对
Hello?
喂
Another win!
又胡了
Thank you!
谢谢哥 谢谢哥啊
Waiter.
伙计伙计 来
I'm out.
不想打了
Bring me
去 跟老板说
some more money.
再拿点儿钱来
More?
再拿点儿钱
Just not my night.
今晚手气不好
Sure,
好嘞哥
I'll go talk to the boss.
我现在给你去说
Sorry about that.
不好意思啊
Mr. Wang.
王哥
Sir!
老板
Mr. Li
老李找你
is asking for more money.
说让你再给他拿点儿
Luo Minmin?
骆珉敏
The female officer
就是被你打伤的
you injured?
那个女警察
The address was sold
孟多慈的地址
on the black market by her brother.
就是她哥哥卖给黑市的
She must know
这个女警察一定知道
where Meng Duoci is.
孟多慈的下落
She's seen your face.
她见过你的样子了
I'll head to her home.
我去骆家吧
Dad! Brother!
爸 哥
What?
怎么了
What happened?
爸
Come here!
你过来
What is it?
怎么了你
Come down now!
你赶紧下来
The... rat ate the meat!
老 老鼠把肉吃了
Where is it?
在哪儿呢
Under... that table!
那 那桌子下面
Where?
哪儿
Come down first!
你先下来你先下来
No, I'm scared!
我不要 我害怕
Just come down!
下来下来
Qinqin?
勤芹
Where's the rat?
老鼠在哪儿
Where is it?
哪儿有老鼠
Where?
你看
What happened?
出什么事儿了
It went under the table.
桌底下去了
Come down!
你下来你下来
No, impossible!
我不下来 我不要啊
It went that way!
那边 那边去了
It's gone.
走了吧
You...
你
Why are you here?
你怎么会在我家
Do you wanna
要不要
go out for a walk?
出去散个步
With me?
跟我
No,
不行
I haven't even washed my face.
我还没洗脸呢
And I'm still in pajamas...
而且我还穿着睡衣
How
这
can I go out like this?
这怎么出去啊
Where is it?
在哪儿呢
It's right inside!
就在里边 里边
I saw it running in!
我看着它跑进去了
Tianxiang, get the flashlight.
天祥去拿手电筒
Okay.
我 我给你拿手电筒
Where did I put it?
手电放哪儿了
Here it is.
在这儿
Dad.
爸 爸
Here you are.
这手 手电
Do him a favor.
哥你快帮爸一起找找
Come down.
下来
I won't.
我不下
You know?
你知道了
Just come down.
下来
Quick.
快快快
Stop drinking that.
别喝了别喝了
Did you bite this?
这你咬的呀
I had no choice.
我也没办法啊
The meat
爸这做的咸肉
is too salty.
也太咸了
You're incredible.
真行
Dad, have you found it?
爸找着了吗爸
No, it might have run off.
没有 可能跑了
No way.
不能
I saw it going under there!
我看见它钻那下面去了
Where is the meat?
来 我看看肉
Here.
肉 肉在这儿
Such a big bite?
这么大一口
It's that big of a rat.
真的 这么大一老鼠呢
It must be huge.
是够大
Maybe I should just come down
要不我自己下来
and try walking.
试着走走吧
Minmin!
珉敏
Dad...
爸 你看
Dad, you got it wrong!
爸 你看错了
Dad!
爸
Minmin!
珉敏
The door is still open...
家里都没锁门
Dad, enough!
行了爸 别追了
Minmin!
珉敏
My dad seems to have wandered off.
我爸爸好像走远了
Did Luo Qinqin
是不是
call you over?
骆勤芹去找你了
No.
没有
It must be.
肯定是她
What did she say to you?
她跟你说什么了
Honestly, no one.
真的没人找我
So, are you coming for me on your own?
那是你自己过来找我的
The boat is shaking.
船在晃
Because of the wind.
对 因为有风
Not necessarily.
不一定是因为有风
Out at sea, there're often swell waves.
海上经常会出现膨胀波
The mechanical gravitational waves
这种机械引力波
could just be
可能是很远的
continuations of distant surges.
涌浪膨胀水体的延续
But they're
只是肉眼
hard to see with the naked eye.
不容易看清楚而已
I see.
我明白了
Because the water is clear.
是因为水是透明的
No, because the wavelength is very long.
因为它的波长很长
You're talking about the sea,
可是你说的是在海上
but we are
我们现在
in a little river channel here.
是在小河沟里呀
Yuansheng,
向警官
before here,
你在当警察之前
were you really a fisherman
真的是在大海上
out at sea every day?
天天捞鱼的渔民啊
Miss Luo,
骆警官
our boat seems to
我们的船
have drifted from the shore.
好像从岸边漂走了
Where are we?
这是在哪儿啊
Up ahead is the river mouth.
前面是入江口
Just beyond that, it's the Huangpu River.
再往前 就到黄浦江了
The Huangpu River?
黄浦江
I haven't been out for days.
我已经好几天没出门了
Do you know how to row?
向警官你会不会划船
Since we've already drifted off,
反正我们都已经漂走了
why don't we
要不我们就
just go a bit further?
走得更远一些吧
Sure.
好
Is it
再往前
the Huangpu River just ahead?
是不是就是黄浦江了
Yes.
对
I've lived in Shanghai all my life,
我从小就生活在上海
seeing the Huangpu River every day.
天天都能看到黄浦江
But I've never actually
但还从来没有
rowed on it.
在黄浦江上划过船
Where does the River
黄浦江再往前
flow to next?
会流到什么地方去啊
The East China Sea,
东海
and finally into the Pacific Ocean.
最后汇入太平洋
The Pacific Ocean?
太平洋
Have you been there?
你到过太平洋
Yes.
去过
How big is it?
太平洋有多大
It's vast.
很大
About several hundred
大概有
thousand times the size of Shanghai.
几十万个上海那么大
Oh my goodness.
几十万个上海
Can you tell me more
那你能给我说说
about the Pacific Ocean?
太平洋吗
At the southernmost tip of China,
在中国的最南端
in the western Pacific Ocean,
太平洋的西海域
there's a territory known as the Nansha Qundao,
有一片领土叫南沙群岛
and a sea called the South China Sea.
有一片海叫南海
I once passed through there by ship.
那一年我坐船经过南海
Lying on deck at night,
夜里躺在甲板上
I saw hundreds of shooting stars
看见几百颗流星
fall from the sky,
从天上坠落
and the Milky Way
看见漫天的星云
slowly sinking into the Ocean.
慢慢地沉入大海
At that moment,
那时候
I felt incredibly small.
我觉得人真的很渺小
Yet, it's amazing
但神奇的是
how our tiny eyes
人渺小的眼睛
can hold such vast expanses.
却能装下所有的辽阔
People aren't really that small.
人其实也没有那么渺小
Right.
对
We are stronger
我们比自己
than we think.
想象的要强大
The places you've mentioned,
你说到的地方
and the sights you've seen,
看过的景色
I've never heard of them before.
我之前从来没有听说过
Luo Qinqin was right.
骆勤芹说得没错
You really do know a lot.
你真的什么都知道
I just knew about them
我只是比你知道得
before you did.
更早一些而已
Now that I've told you,
我现在告诉你了
don't you know them too?
你不也知道了
Besides,
再说
there are things
也有你会
you can do that I can't.
但是我不会的东西啊
Really?
真的
Like what?
是什么
Martial arts gymnastics.
武技体操
You can do gymnastics,
你会武技体操
but I can't.
我就不会
I learned it
那是因为我之前
during police training.
上警察培训的时候学的
But I only know some movements.
不过也只是学会了而已
If you were to learn,
如果是你去学的话
you'd have been better at it than me.
你肯定练得比我更好
You and my sister
你和我妹妹骆勤芹
are the same,
都一样
able to
是那种
understand a book at a glance,
看书一眼就能看会
excelling
学东西
at anything you learn.
一学就能拿到第一名
You know what kind of person I am?
你知道我是哪种人吗
Your dad once said,
骆先生说过
you may get
珉敏是那种
answers wrong
就算给她答案
even if they're given to you,
她也会抄错的人
learn slowly,
学东西很慢
and may not apply and make good use
学了也不一定会
of the knowledge you've learned in practice.
会了也不一定能做好
For example,
就像你虽然
you went through police training,
参加过警察培训
but when truly
但真正和凶手
face-to-face with a criminal,
面对面的时候
you lack the ability
你也没有能力
to protect yourself.
保护好自己
Basically,
基本可以说是
you can't do much.
什么都不会
Why did he say these about me?
我爸爸怎么跟你说这些
But I asked myself,
但我问过我自己
if I knew as little
如果我和你一样
as you,
什么都不会
facing the killer that night,
那天晚上面对凶手
would I have the courage
我是否和你一样
to fight back like you did?
有勇气跟他拼命
I doubt
我想
I would.
我不一定会有
Most people probably wouldn't.
大部分人也许都不会有
Being strong is not always about capability.
有的强大与能力无关
That's
这是之前
what I had never considered before.
我从来没有想过的
Who let the guy in?
谁把那个人放进来的
Speak up!
说话
Say it!
说话呀
Wait.
来了
You actually teamed up
翅膀硬了
to deceive me.
合起来骗我
Sorry to bother.
你好
May I ask
请问
if Mr. Luo Tianxiang lives here?
这里是骆天祥先生家吗
Who might you be?
你是哪位
I'm a friend of him.
我是骆先生的朋友
He's been called to the mahjong parlor.
麻将馆叫他帮忙去了
Is Miss Luo in then?
那骆警官在吗
I heard she's injured on duty.
听说她执行任务受了伤
I'm a columnist.
我是专栏作家
I'd like to write for her bravery.
想写篇文章替她做宣传
My son doesn't have
我儿子呢
any friends from Japan.
没有日本朋友
My daughter is no longer a police officer.
我女儿也不做警察了
Miss Luo must know
那骆警官应该知道
where the girl she saved is,
她救的那个女孩儿
right?
在哪儿吧
Meeting Meng Duoci would also work.
让我见孟多慈也可以
I don't know any Meng Duoci,
我不认识孟多慈
and we're not interested in publicity.
我们也不做宣传
Is this where Miss Luo lives?
骆警官家是在这边吧
Yes,
对啊
it's supposed to be at No. 55.
就说是五十五号的
No. 55?
五十五号
This is No. 38.
这是三十八号
So it must be further down.
那应该再往前吧
This is so annoying!
怎么这么讨厌呢
Um, well...
那个 伯父
we're here for Minmin.
来看看珉敏
Dad.
爸
How did you all get here?
你们怎么来了
Minmin,
珉敏
you're finally back.
你可算回来了
We've been waiting for you.
我们等了你好久
She's already here.
人都已经回来了
You can
各位
leave with all you have.
拎着东西回吧
Tianxiang.
天祥
See the guests out.
送客
Dad.
爸
They're my friends...
他们是我的朋友
Qinqin.
勤芹
Take your sister upstairs!
把你姐带上去
Dad, Minmin is right.
爸 珉敏说得对
These are her friends...
这都是她朋友
You call them friends?
这些算朋友吗
And you!
还有你
Make friends with Japanese?
还认识日本朋友啊
I... I don't know any.
我 我不认识啊
There's a man coming
刚才有个人
for someone called Meng Duoci.
找什么孟什么多慈的